Finding Aid for John C. Early Papers, 1911-1942
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
John C. Early Papers 1911-1942, 1911-1932
Early, John C. (John Chrysostom), 1878-1932.
0.4 linear ft. and 1 oversize folder
Teacher and administrator in the Philippines, governor of the Mountain Province, 1923-1930, later advisor to the Governor General on non-Christian affairs; correspondence, reminiscences, speeches, articles, and photographs.
85532 Aa 2
Bentley Historical Library University of Michigan
The collection was the gift of Frederic S. Marquardt (donor no. 5131 ) who donated Early's reminiscence in 1972 and Frank L. Jenista (donor no. 5804 ) who donated the remainder of the collection in 1976.
The collection is open for research.
John C. Early was a teacher and administrator in the Philippine Islands. He was governor of the Mountain Province, 1923-1930, then later advisor to the governor general on non-Christian affairs.
The John C. Early collection consists of two series: Papers and Photographs. The Papers series includes correspondence, reminiscences, speeches, and articles written by Early, primarily relating to his experiences in the Philipppines and papers of Willa R. Early. Correspondents represented in the collection include Charles H. Brent, James Fugate, Gouverneur Frank Mosher, Henry L. Stimson, and Leonard Wood. The Photograph series includes photos of Early, his family, and other American officials in the Philippines. There are also photos of the Philippine countryside, cities, and people, especially views of the Mountain Province.
Subjects:
Early, John C. (John Chrysostom), 1878-1932.; Philippines--History--1898-1946.; Teachers--Philippines.
Subjects - Visual Material:
Early, John C. (John Chrysostom), 1878-1932.; Early family.; Governors--Philippines.; Philippines--History--1898-1946.
Contributors:
Brent, Charles Henry, 1862-1929.; Early, Willa R. (Willa Rhodes), 1883-; Fugate, James, 1877-1938.; Mosher, Gouverneur Frank, 1871-1941.; Stimson, Henry Lewis, 1867-1950.; Wood, Leonard, 1860-1927.
Genre/Form:
Photographs.
- Papers
  - Correspondence
    - Undated, 1911-1920 (Box 1)
    - 1921-1928 (Box 1)
    - 1929-1932 (Box 1)
  - Speeches and writings (Box 1)
  - Article, "Home of the Luzon Highlander" (Box 1)
  - Miscellanea (Box 1)
  - Willa Rhodes Early
    - Correspondence, 1923-1942 (Box 1)
    - Miscellanea (Box 1)
  - Reminiscence of John C. Early (1906-1923), 1931, 1 volume (Box 1)
- Photographs
  - Philippine buildings, cities, towns (Box 1)
  - Philippine countryside (especially views of Mountain Province) (Box 1)
  - Family, friends, unidentified people (American) (Box 1)
  - Official groups and functions (Box 1)
  - Residences (Box 1)
  - Unidentified people (Box 1)